Peyton B. Locker Business; Papers mss082
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Peyton B. Locker Business Papers
1920-1951
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss082
.82 cubic ft.
The collection contains the business records of Peyton B. Locker from his time in the petroleum, gas, and mining business.
Collection X
Biographical History
Born in Virginia, Peyton B. Locker (1873-1955) was an American businessman and entrepreneur. He was involved in the mining, petroleum and gas industries in the mid twentieth century and lived in New York City. In 1929, Peyton B. Locker created the Locker process for petroleum refinement which was created alongside the Harris oil-gas plant established by an associate, Leonard B. Harris. This product and process allowed for improvements in the extraction and refinement of gas/petroleum products which led to several patents.
This process and the accompanying plant formed the basis of the creation of the International Oil-Gas Corporation in the state of Delaware in 1931. Locker acted as the treasurer of the International Oil-Gas Corporation from its formation until the mid-1940s in New York City. Throughout the 1930s and 1940s Locker was involved in several possible petroleum and mining activities throughout the United States, Columbia, Bolivia, Venezuela, and Panama.
In 1949, Peyton B. Locker was living in Westchester, New York. He involved in the creation of a mining company alongside Luis Creel and W. C. Webster. The company was founded in Mexico City, Mexico. The Piedra Iman Mining Company sought to extract iron ore for exportation to Europe and operated in Acapulco within the state of Guerrero in Mexico.
He died in July 1955.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the business records of Peyton B. Locker from his time in the petroleum, gas and mining business. It contains a variety of formats including correspondences, blueprints, memorandums, administrative, financial, legal and geological records from his time in these industries.
The majority of these materials relate to the International Oil-Gas Corporation's operations in the United States including the company's founding, board meetings, business processes, technical patents/intellectual property, equipment production, and communications (1931-1944). This includes a series of legal matters the company underwent in 1930s and the company's financing and billing records.
Another large component of the records contains information Mining Companies including geological reports on ore, business contracts, financing documents and land agreements complete with maps.
The collection also contains advertising materials and reports surrounding a variety of mining ventures in the United States, Central and South America through the in 1930s and 1940s.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are no series.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased from dealer Dauber in 1967.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Business and Industry; Locker, Peyton B. (1873-1955); International Oil-Gas Corporation; International Oil-Gas Corporation
- Administrative Overview, 1931; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alaska Mining Materials, 1937; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Alaskan Mining Materials Maps, 1937 (Flat-file 1)
- Blueprints for International Oil-Gas, 1939 (Flat-file 2)
- Bol-inca Mining Corporation and Bolivian Mining, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Connecticut Tax Matters and Payroll, 1939-1943; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- East Texas Crude Oil, 1937; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Frank P. Parish, 1934-1935; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General Business Correspondence, 1920-1946; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- General Business Correspondence, 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- General Business Reports and Memos, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- General Business Reports and Memos, Maps, Undated (Flat-file 3)
- Harris, Leonard B., 1931; 1935-1936; 1940-1941; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Harris Oil Steam Generator and Early Company Materials, 1929-1933; 1935; 1939-1940; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Harris Oil Steam Generator and its Functions, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- International Oil and Gas Corporation Charter, By laws and Meeting Minutes, 1931-1935; 1937-1939; Undated (Oversized 1)
- International Oil-Gas Corporation Financing and Billing, 1931-1937; 1939; 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- International Oil and Gas Corporation Meeting Minutes, 1940-1944 (Oversized 1)
- Leonard B. Harris v. International Oil-Gas Corp., 1934-1935; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Locker Process Reports and Records, 1934-1935; 1937; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Mining Newspaper Reports, 1949-1950; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Mining Project Valle Citos Mine. Anori, Columbia, 1934; 1937-1938; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- North Carolina Nickle Project, 1937-1938; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- North Carolina Nickle Project Maps, Undated (Flat-file 4)
- Northern Mining Syndicate, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Panama Development Reports, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Personal Correspondence and Other Materials, 1921; 1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Personal Correspondence and Other Materials, Maps, 1926 (Flat-file 5)
- Venezuela Mining Syndicate, 1932; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Venezuela Reports, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Venezuela Reports Maps, 1931 (Flat-file 6)
- Webster Contracts, 1947-1951; Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Report for Mr. P. B. Locker on Piedra Iman Properties and Docks at Puerto Marques, 1949-1951; Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Yes. Record contains attorney-client privilege and is therefore closed for 75 years - December 31, 2026